Preliminary Inventory of the Alex Inkeles papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- "National Character" project, 1988-1989 (Box 382-388)
  - Data analysis; regression analysis; correlation (Box 386-387)
  - Japan; individualism; comparative values (Box 388)
- "Quality of Life" project (Box 388)
  - Topics: "Happiness," including conference paper on topic, 1991; Ecology; China (Box 388)
- Various research projects, 1980-1999 (Box 388)
  - Convergence in educational systems, 1980-1983; Adolescence studies, 1998-1999; Social capital, 1998 (Box 389)
  - Transitions in Eastern Europe, 1991-1995; Lee Walker (National Research Council), correspondence regarding sponsored workshops and papers (Box 390)
  - Modernization; Research assistant correspondence and instructions, 1994 (Box 391)
  - Adolescence study, including surveys and collected data from various locations (Bulgaria, California, Chile, Colorado, North Carolina), 1991-1994 (Box 392)
  - Chinese modernity project, survey and data, 1992; Retirement project, survey and data, 1993 (Box 393)
- Research support, containing files on grants sought and received, from Guggenheim Foundation, Fulbright Program, Council for the International Exchange of Scholars, Carnegie Council, and others, 1974-1992 (Box 394-395)
- "World Order" project (Box 395-397)
  - Manuscript drafts of papers, conferences, 1973-1994 (Box 395-396)
  - Unpublished papers by others, 1973-1976 (Box 397)
- "Adolescence" project (Box 397-398)
  - Collected data, 1997-1998 (Box 397)
  - "Adolescence and Cooperation in Japan," manuscript drafts of paper, data analysis, correspondence with research assistants, 1998 (Box 398)
  - Japan, outcomes by category; parent-child comparisons in Japan and Colorado; autonomy, 1998-1999 (Box 399-400)
  - "Japanese character," 1985-1986 (Box 401)
  - Projects with Herbert Leiderman, including present at Stanford University, Family Center, 1994; validity of data, 1993-1994 (Box 402)
  - Data analyses, correspondence with research assistants, 1992-1993, 1996 (Box 403-404)
  - Questionnaires, 1991-1997 (Box 405-406)
  - Comparison scale structure, 1997; Singapore material, 2002 (Box 406)
  - Data analysis for Colorado, 1996-1997; North Carolina, 1994; Switzerland, 1994 (Box 407)
  - Chile, 1990-1995 (Box 408-409)
  - Bulgaria, including research conducted by Luba Botcheva, with data scales, questionnaires, correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 410)
- Miscellaneous files, including alphabetic correspondence to be filed, 1991-1994; Japan-U.S. data; U.S.-Chile adolescence study, with drafts of paper by Alex Inkeles and Herbert Leiderman (Box 411)
- Research topics, varied (Box 412)
  - "World systems," conference papers and other unpublished papers by others
  - "Dependency," conference papers and other unpublished papers by others (Box 412-413)
  - "Marriage and family" (Box 413)
  - "Convergence Seminar," (course taught by Inkeles at Stanford), 1987 (Box 413)
  - "Convergence," correspondence with research assistants and other scholars about data and methodology, 1983 (Box 414)
  - "India," collected data and memoranda, 2000-2001 (Box 414)
  - "National character," bibliography compiled for Inkeles, 1988 (Box 415)
  - "Adolescence," data analysis and memoranda, 2001 (Box 415)
  - "Adolescence," data on school outcomes, 2001 (Box 416)
  - Research topics, varied (Box 416)
  - "Aging," unpublished papers and correspondence from other scholars, 1982-1986 (Box 416)
  - Editorial correspondence from publishers of works by Inkeles (Box 417)
  - Unpublished papers and correspondence from other scholars, various topics, 1980-1986 (Box 417)
  - "Amnon file," 1968-1973 (Box 417)
  - "Youth attitude survey," conducted with Richard Suzman, 1976-1977, questionnaires and outcomes (Box 418)
- "China projects" (Box 418-419)
  - Correspondence with Chinese scholars, as well as with Hoover fellow Thomas Metzger, 1985-1997 (Box 418-419)
  - China Survey project, 1993-1995, papers from other scholars, survey design, correspondence (Box 418-419)
  - "National character" (Box 420-421)
- Papers from other scholars, 1955-1979 (Box 420)
  - "National Character" chapter by Alex Inkeles and Dan Levinson in the book Handbook of Social Psychology, correspondence and manuscript drafts, 1967-1968 (Box 420-421)
  - Francis Hsu (Northwestern University), 1969-1970 (Box 421)
  - "Continuity and Change in the American Character," talk by Alex Inkeles at Hoover Institution, 1977 (Box 421)
  - Papers by other scholars (Box 421)
- Correspondence, general (Box 421-424)
  - 1996-1997, includes conferences attended, book reviews, activity report (Hoover Institution) (Box 421-423)
  - Colleagues (Box 423)
    - Hoover Institution, 1978 (Box 423)
    - International: Latin America, North America, Europe, 1961-1993 (Box 423)
    - International: Western Europe (continued), Near East, Far East, 1960-1985 (Box 424)
- "Japan-U.S." projects, with focus on examining maturity and parent-child relationships, autonomy and cooperation, 1998-2000, includes survey results, data analysis, scales and scale construction, correspondence with research assistants, background data (Box 425-427)
- Courses taught by Alex Inkeles, Stanford University (Box 428-433)
  - World Systems, 1980-1987, includes course abstracts, reading lists, syllabi, lecture notes, student evaluations, and examination questions (Box 428-431)
  - Personality and Social Structures, 1971-1979, includes syllabi, reading lists, lecture notes (Box 431-432)
  - Modernization seminar, 1972-1973 (Box 432)
  - Seminar on organizations, 1974-1976 (Box 433)
- Writings: Drafts of papers, publication correspondence (Box 433)
  - "Institution Building Essential for Successful Transition to Democracy," presented at U.S. Agency for International Development conference, Washington, June 1991 (Box 434)
  - "Polish Road from Socialism," co-edited by Alex Inkeles, 1992 (Box 434)
  - Book review by Alex Inkeles, of Nationalism: Five Roads to Modernity," by Liah Greenfield, 1993 (Box 434)
  - "A Century of Procedural Due Process Guarantees in Constitutions Worldwide," by Alex Inkeles and Jon Hooper, 1993 (Box 434)
  - "Industrialization and Modernization and the Quality of Life," keynote address at the International Institute of Sociology congress, Kobe, August 1991 (Box 434-435)
  - "Linking the Whole Human Race: The World as a Communication System,", 1988 (Box 435)
  - "Rethinking Social Welfare: The U.S. and U.S.S.R. in Comparative Perspective,", 1986 (Box 435)
  - "The Retirement Decision in Cross National Perspective,", 1987 (Box 435)
  - "The Olympics in the World Communication System," proposed talk for planned conference in Seoul, 1987 (Box 435)
  - "On Measuring Democracy,", 1991-1994 (Box 435)
  - "What the U.S. Agency for International Development Can Do for the Transition to Democracy,", 1991 (Box 436)
- Copyright: Forms filed to protect own work, requests from others to publish work of Inkeles, 1959-1990 (Box 436-437)
- Publications in process, 1988-1994 (Box 437)
- Guest lectures: Notes, texts, and background material, arranged by subject (Box 438-442)
  - Individual and modernity; national traits and modernity; convergence (Box 438)
  - World systems; economic growth and development (Box 439)
  - National character; social sciences; social psychology (Box 440)
  - Social psychology (continued); United States of America; Various topics (Box 441)
  - World systems (Box 442)
- Various files from desk, 1998-2002 (Box 443-451)
  - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 443)
  - Hoover Institution, activity reports from Inkeles, 1997-1999 (Box 443)
  - Publications in process (manuscript drafts, editorial correspondence), 1999 (Box 443)
  - Reviews, 1999 (Box 443)
  - Travel, conferences attended, 1998-1999 (Box 443)
  - Travel, continued (Box 444)
  - Visitors, 1998-1999 (Box 444)
  - Papers from other scholars, 1998-1999 (Box 444)
  - Correspondence, general, 1998-1999 (Box 445)
  - Papers, in conjunction with other scholars (Herbert Leiderman, Maureen Hallinan, M. Sasaki, Galin Gornev, Paul Rich, Jie Shen), 1999-2000 (Box 445)
  - Research support, 1998-2001 (Box 446)
  - Travel and conferences, 1999-2000 (Box 446)
  - Visitors, 2000-2002 (Box 447)
  - Publications in process (chiefly Social Capital project), 2000 (Box 447)
  - Workshop on Regional Transitions, Stanford University, November 2002 (Box 447)
  - Projects: "Social Capital," 1999; "Universal Values," 1999-2001 (Box 448)
  - Correspondence, Thomas Metzger, along with annotated papers from him, 1995-2003 (Box 449-450)
  - China visit, circa 1981: notebooks, translated lectured (Box 450)
  - Correspondence, Cao Zhongde, 1993 (Box 450)
  - File on OSS personnel from social sciences (copies of documents from National Archives) (Box 450)
  - "Adolescence/Maturity" study, survey basic data from United States, 1998 (Box 451)
- Biographical materials, CV, and bibliographies, through circa 1993 (Box 452)
- Writings: Reprints of articles by Alex Inkeles, 1946-1993 (Box 452-458)
  - Reprint Index, 1946-1993 (Box 452)
  - Reprints, # 1-10, 1946-1950 (Box 452)
  - Reprints, # 11-35, 1951-1960 (Box 453)
  - Reprints, # 36-60, 1960-1972 (Box 454)
  - Reprints, # 61-85, 1973-1977 (Box 455)
  - Reprints, # 86-105, 1978-1983 (Box 456)
  - Reprints, # 106-124 (no 113, 119, 121), 1983-1990 (Box 457)
  - Reprints, # 125-138 (no 132, 134), 1991-2002 (Box 458)
  - Book Reviews reprints, 1988-1993 (Box 459)
  - Russia articles, 1949-1959 (Box 459)
  - Study Group on Convergence in Industrial Society; North/South Issues reprints, 1978 (Box 459)
- Audiocassettes: Interviews from Michal Tamuz, 1990-1994 (Box 459)
- Special projects (conferences, research projects, etc.) (Box 460-480)
  - 1965-1966 (Box 460)
  - 1967 (Box 461)
  - 1967-1968 (Box 462)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 463)
  - 1969 (Box 464)
  - 1969-1970 (Box 465)
  - 1970 (Box 466)
  - 1970-1971 (Box 467)
  - 1971 (Box 468)
  - 1971 (Box 469)
  - 1972/73 (Box 470)
  - 1972/73-1973/74 (Box 471)
  - 1973/74 (Box 472)
  - 1973/74-1975 (Box 473)
  - 1975 (Box 474)
  - 1975 (Box 475)
  - 1975-1976, plus courses taught in 1975 (Box 476)
  - 1976 (Box 477)
  - 1976 (Box 478)
  - 1976-1977 (Box 479)
  - 1977 (Box 480)
- Chronological (outgoing) correspondence, 1972-1977 (Box 480-484)
  - March-December 1971 (Box 480)
  - January-December 1972, January-May 1973 (Box 481)
  - June-December 1973, January-December 1974, January-June 1975 (Box 482)
  - July-December 1975, January-October 1976 (Box 483)
  - November 1976-December 1977 (Box 484)
- Writing and research (Box 485)
  - "Personality and Social Structure," proposed book, 1979; correspondence with Chris Wilkes, research assistant (Box 485)
- Sabbatical in Israel, September-December 1979; mail forwarded to Inkeles from his office at Hoover, includes correspondence, notes, writings, financial records (Box 485-488)
- Grant funded projects. Includes research projects funded by National Science Foundation, U.S. Air Force, National Institute of Mental Health, N.I.H., 1963-1977 (Box 488-491)
- Various topics, 1974-1975 (Box 492)
  - Richard Suzman (Box 492)
  - Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton (Box 492)
  - Mendes, Candido (Brazil) (Box 492)
  - Religion and modernism (Box 492)
  - Personality and Social Structure (Oxford Univ. Press) (Box 492)
  - Psychology and society discussion group, Princeton (Box 492)
  - Hodgkins, B.J., "School/climates" (Box 492)
- Papers (unpublished) by various scholars, 1972-1974 (Box 493-494)
- Becoming Modern: Individual Change in Six Developing Countries,, 1973-1974, chapter drafts, contract, correspondence, tables and charts (Box 495)
- Exploring Individual Modernity, 1981-1983. Chapter drafts, correspondence, tables and charts (Box 496-499)
- Special projects, 1981-1982 (Box 499)
- Various topics, 1981-1982 (Box 500)
- Hoover Institution administration (Box 500)
  - Trips cancelled (Box 500)
  - Teaching, including Pro-seminar on Sociology, Sociology 10, and Subcommittee on Evaluation of Improvement of Teaching (Box 500)
  - Trips (Box 500)
  - American Sociological Association annual meeting, 1982 (Box 500)
  - Bellagio Study and Conference Center (Box 501)
  - World Association for International Relations (WAIR) (Box 501)
  - Undergraduate advising (Box 501)
- Stanford University, committees, 1981-1982 (Box 501)
  - Latin American Studies committee (Box 501)
  - Asia Forum (Box 501)
  - Organization Committee (Box 501)
  - Monticello West (Box 501)
  - CROW Seminar (Box 501)
  - Values, Technology and Society in the Middle East (seminar series) (Box 501)
- Papers, by various scholars (Box 502)
  - "What is Sociology?" research gathered for book with same title by Inkeles (Box 502)
  - Whyte, William Allen (Box 502)
- Various topics, 1973 (Box 503)
  - SEADAG (Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Asia Society), papers submitted for seminars (Box 503)
  - International Committee on Social...Development, Dubrovnik (Box 503)
- Sabbatical in Israel, September-December 1979. Van Leer Jerusalem Foundation, papers on seminars, and correspondence (Box 504)
- Special projects, 1981-1982 (Box 505)
  - Amnesty International (Box 505)
  - Scientists for Sakharov, Orlov, Shcharansky (Box 505)
  - International Sociology Association, conference, Mexico City, 1982 (Box 506)
- Stanford University (Box 506)
  - University committees (Box 506)
  - Guest lectures (Box 506)
  - Sociology department (Box 506)
  - Visitors (Box 506)
  - Outside committees (Box 506)
  - CERAS (Center for Educational Research at Stanford), Institute for Research on Educational Financing and Governance, 1978-1984 (Box 507)
    - Proposals, research and budget (Box 507)
    - Seminars, research assistants (Box 508-509)
- Sabbatical in Israel, September-December 1979. Correspondence with assistant at Hoover Institution, and forwarded correspondence (Box 509)
- Stanford University, 1980-1981 (Box 509)
  - Northeast Asia Forum (Box 509)
  - EDGE (Ethics of Development in a Global Environment) (Box 509)
  - Visitors (Box 509)
  - Pro-seminars (sociology graduate students) (Box 510)
  - Finances (Box 510)
  - WAIR / Psomas (Box 510)
- Chronological (outgoing) correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 510-514)
  - January-July 1978 (Box 510)
  - August 1978-March 1979 (Box 511)
  - April 1979-December 1979 (Box 512)
  - May 1980-October 1980 (Box 513)
  - November 1980-December 1980 (Box 514)
- Trips, 1989-1990 (Poland, Bulgaria) (Box 514)
- Various topics (Box 515)
  - AAAS Conference, 1977 (Box 515)
  - "Jacobs study," International Studies of Values in Politics, University of Pennsylvania, 1966-1968 (Box 515)
- Special projects, 1978-1979 (Box 516)
  - "Institute study group" (world system, convergence), Royal Institute of International Affairs, Chatham House, London (Box 516)
  - Richard Suzman, 1978 (Box 516)
  - "Exploring Individual Modernity," proposal, 1978 (Box 516)
  - William Rau, "Modernity," 1979 (Box 516)
  - Scientists for Sakharov, Orlov, and Shcharansky, 1979 (Box 516)
  - Assembly Bill 46 (California State Assembly) (Box 516)
  - "Lunch prospects" (seminars), 1979 (Box 516)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities proposal (S.M. Lipset), 1978 (Box 516)
- Stanford University (Box 516-519)
  - Teaching, Stanford University, 1978-1979 (Box 516)
  - Assistants, 1978 (Box 516)
- CLOSED (Box 517-519)
- Special projects, 1979-1980 (Box 520)
  - Boys Town (Box 520)
  - Van Leer Foundation, Israel (Box 520)
  - ASA Conference, Boston (Box 520)
  - Others (Box 520)
- Special projects, 1980-1981 (Box 521)
  - Conferences attended (Box 521)
  - Book reviews (Box 521)
  - Interviews (Box 521)
  - Northeast Asia Forum, Stanford University, 1980-1981 (Box 521)
  - Amnesty International (Box 522)
- Special projects, 1981-1982 (Box 522)
  - Conferences attended (Box 522)
  - Pro-seminar, Stanford University (Box 522)
  - Berlin conference: paper in response to work by Deutsch, et. al., "Sociological Contributions to the Social Sciences;" correspondence, manuscript drafts, source material (Box 523)
- Special projects, 1982-1983 (Box 523)
  - Amnesty International (Box 523)
  - Monticello West (Box 523)
  - VTS, Stanford University (Box 523)
  - ASA conference (Box 524)
  - IIASA Academy (Box 524)
  - World Bank (Box 524)
  - Center for Research on the Acts of Man (University of Pennsylvania), "Parsons Project" (paper on government support of the social sciences) (Box 524)
  - Due process project (Box 525)
  - Wright Institute (Box 525)
  - Local activities (primarily Stanford University), 1983-1984 (Box 525)
- Chilean conference, 1984 (Box 525)
- Chronological (outgoing) correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 525)
  - January-November 1984 (Box 526)
  - December 1984-February 1986 (Box 527)
  - March 1986-December 1986 (Box 528)
- Projects with or from other scholars (Box 528)
  - "Spencer manuscript, 1-7-1974" (Box 529)
  - Suzman, Richard, "An Analysis of the OM Scale in the Third District Electoral Survey, June 1971" (Box 529)
    - Introduction, Appendix, Chapters 2-4 (Box 529)
    - Chapters 5-8 (Box 530)
  - "Race, Racism": Various sociological studies, grouped by institutions, including National Opinion Research Center, University of Chicago; Center for Comparative Racial and Ethnic Studies, State University of New York, Buffalo; 1966-1967 (Box 530)
  - Sociological Research Association (Box 530)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the Peoples Republic of China, National Academy of Sciences, Washington DC, January 1986 (Box 531)
  - Rosen, Stanley, research on the Peoples Republic of China, 1987 (Box 531)
  - Joint Center on Urban Studies, Massachusetts Institute of Technology-Harvard University, "Boston Area Study," 1969 (Box 531)
  - Brazilian conferences, 1968-1969 (Box 531)
  - Projects with or from other scholars (Box 531)
  - Fried, Marc (Boston College), surveys and research on urban and rural migration, 1968-1969 (Box 532)
  - Katz, Zev, untitled sociological study on the Soviet Union (manuscript drafts), 1986 (Box 532)
    - Books I and II (Box 533)
    - Books III and IV (Box 534)
    - Bibliography and notes (Box 535)
  - Assorted papers sent to Inkeles by other scholars, with attached correspondence (Box 535)
- Writings by Alex Inkeles (Box 536)
  - "Social Structures and the Socialization of Competence," drafts, notes, correspondence, 1966 (Box 536)
- Becoming Modern: Individual Change in Six Developing Countries, (Harvard University Press, 1974) research materials, 1966-1974 (Box 536)
  - Bibliographical material abstracts and paper by Natalie J. Sokoloff (OG copy) (Box 537)
    - Book I, Parts 1-2 (Folder 537: 1-2)
    - Book II, Parts 1-2 (Folder 537: 3-4)
    - Book III (Folder 537: 5)
  - Matches vs. Selected OM Scales and 19 OM Subscales, all Countries, Vol. I and II (Folder 538: 1-2)
  - EFFRAT, abstracts, bibliography (Folder 538: 3)
  - IV reports, Vol. I and II, Part 1 (Folder 538: 4)
  - IV reports, Vol. I and II, Part 2 (Folder 539: 1)
  - Non-IV project papers, 1965-March 1967 (Folder :)
    - Vol. I, copy 2, Part 1 (Folder 539: 2-3)
    - Vol. II, copy 2, Parts 1-2 (Folder 539: 4-5)
    - Vol. III, copy 2, Parts 1-2 (Folder 540: 1-2)
    - Vol. IV, copy 1, Parts 1-2 (Folder 540: 3-4)
    - Vol. IV, copy 1, Parts 1-2 (Folder 540: 5-6)
    - Vol. VI, copy 2 (Folder 541: 1)
  - Project on the Social and Cultural Aspects of Development, Book IV, card 24 codebook (Corresponds to Book IV sent to Roper) (Folder 541: 2)
  - Project on the Social and Cultural Aspects of Development, Book VIII, card 87 codebook (Folder 541: 3)
  - "The Factory as a School in Social Change," R. Ireland, first and final versions, Dec. 1968 - May 1969 (Folder 541: 4-5)
  - Pakistan: Factory reports (Transcripts of Dr. Schumann's Tapes), Set I (Folder 541: 6)
  - Curvilinearity Graphs, copy 2 (Folder 541: 7)
  - "Ideales, Expectativas, y Aspiraciones en el Obrero Chileno" Juan Cesar Garcia (Folder 542: 1)
  - "A Psychological Study of Student Leaves of Absence from Harvard" Eric Wright, 1968 (Folder 542: 2)
  - "Characteristics and Attitudes of Modernity of Teacher Candidates in the Eastern and Western Regions of Canada" John Frederick Pyra, Parts 1 and 2 (Folder 542: 3-4)
  - "The Relationship between Modernity and Academic Performance in Students in a Puerto Rican High School, Their Parents, and Peers" Ineke Cunningham (Folder 542: 5)
  - "Political Attitudes in Transitional Environments" Günter S. Boroschek, Parts 1 and 2 (Folder 543: 1-2)
  - "Subjective Efficacy as an Aspect of Modernization in Six Developing Nations" John Williamson, Parts 1 and 2 (Folder 543: 3-4)
  - "Some Social and Psychological Factors Affecting Commitment to Industrial Employment in Nigeria" Olatunde Oloko, Parts 1 and 2 (Folder 543: 5-6)
  - Index to alphabetical items, copy 1 (Folder 544: 1)
  - OM Book (Folder 544: 2)
  - Question alphabetical listing (Folder 544: 3)
  - Listing of behavioral items, Tepperman (Folder 544: 4)
  - Sampling and background data, copy 1 (Folder 544: 5-6)
  - Factory data codebook, copy 1 (library copy) (Folder 545: 1)
  - Basic data information (Folder 545: 2)
  - Staff meeting minutes, library copy (Folder 545: 3)
  - "Testing a Single-Factor Model as an Alternative to the Misuse of Partial Correlations in Hypothesis-Testing Research" (Folder 545: 4)
  - Israel, student questionnaire (Folder 545: 5)
  - Questionnaire, "Topical Ordering of Items," 1966 (Folder 545: 6)
  - Scale reliabilities, 6/18/1971 (Folder 545: 7)
  - HUPSCAD Questionnaire, Original Manuscript Version, Vol. I (Folder 546: 1-2)
  - Book III, Supplemental Sections, Fact Sheet, Miscellaneous, Seminar Meeting Notes (Folder 546: 3-4)
  - Harvard University Project on the Socio-Cultural Aspects of Development as Filed with Library of Congress, supplementary material (Folder 546: 5)
  - Harvard Project on the Socio-Cultural Aspects of Development, general coding and punching log (Folder 547: 1)
  - Inkeles Project, computer info: write-ups for 360 and 7094 programs (Folder 547: 2)
  - Behavior material, Shirley Weitz, August 1968 (Folder 547: 3)
  - Basic A, C, I, S, N, P, country information (Folder 547: 4)
  - Staff Meeting Notes, summer 1965, spring 1966 (Folder 547: 5)
  - Nigeria field report (Folder 547: 6)
  - D 1-8 (Folder 547: 7)
  - Project on the Social and Cultural Aspects of Development, Standard English version of the questionnaire (Folder 547: 8)
  - India, alphabetical index (Folder 547: 9)
  - Pakistan, alphabetical index (Folder 547: 10)
  - Nigeria, alphabetical index (Folder 547: 11)
  - Israel, alphabetical index (Folder 547: 12)
  - Argentina, alphabetical index (Folder 548: 1)
  - Chile, alphabetical index (with pencil corrections and final) (Folder 548: 2)
  - Various works by Howard Schuman (Folder 548: 3)
    - "Social Change and the Validity of Regional Stereotypes in East Pakistan" (Folder 548: 3)
    - "Economic Development and Individual Change: A Social-Psychological Study of the Comilla Experiment in Pakistan" (Folder 548: 3)
    - "Social Changes and the Validity of Regional Stereotypes in East Pakistan" (Folder 548: 3)
    - "The Random Probe: A Technique for Evaluating the Validity of Closed Questions" (Folder 548: 3)
  - "City as an Explanatory Variable in the Study of Racial Attitudes" by Howard Schuman, with correspondence from Alex Inkeles (Folder 548: 4)
  - Howard Schuman writings (Folder 548: 5)
  - Amar Kumar Singh correspondence and a list of HUPSCAD Indian essays (Folder 548: 6)
  - "Industrialization, Modernization and Economic Development in India" (Folder 548: 7)
  - "A Cross-Cultural Measure of Modernity and Some Popular Indian Images," Amar Kumar Singh (Folder 548: 8)
  - HUPSCAD India papers (Folder 548:)
    - What Cities and Factories Do to Rural Migrants: Dehumanization or Modernization? (Folder 548: 9)
    - Duration of Factory Experience and Changing Attitudes to Social and Political Elite (Folder 548: 10)
    - Report on the Field Work in India (Folder 548: 11)